Guide to the Priscilla Morgan Papers, 1910-2014 (bulk 1945-2014)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
- Series I. Subject Files
  - NOGUCHI, ISAMU
    - Proposals for Museum in Mure, Japan, 1992-2000 (19.2)
    - Scroll and sculpture inventories, 1973-1987 (19.3)
    - Segerstrom, Orange County Spring Festival proposal, 2007-2011 (19.4)
    - SUNY Purchase loan, "The Bow", 1971-1974 (19.5)
    - Threlfall, Tim, Noguchi text, 1989-1990 (19.6)
  - NOGUCHI MUSEUM
    - Affidavit (P. Morgan) re sale of artwork to support Noguchi Foundation, 2004-2006 (19.7)
    - Akari Foundation certificate of incorporation, Noguchi Foundation Board minutes, 1967-1984 (19.8)
    - Benefit event, 2010 May (19.9)
    - Board minutes, reports, memoranda, 1983-1985 (19.10 - 19.11)
    - Board minutes, Noguchi Foundation, 1986-2008 (19.12 - 19.15, 20.1)
    - Budgets, 1989-1992 (20.2 - 20.3)
    - Building estimates, construction, 1974 (20.4)
    - Correspondence, 2004-2012 (20.5 - 20.7)
    - Exhibition logistics, Japan, 1992 (20.8)
    - Fundraising, 1997-2003 (20.9)
    - Fundraising events, 2004-2007 (20.10)
    - Grand reopening, 2004 (20.11)
    - Morgan, Priscilla, consultancy to museum, 1995, 2004 (20.12)
    - Museum collection policy review, 2009-2010 (20.13)
    - Museum director search, 1989-1990 (20.14)
    - Noguchi Foundation agreements, 1993-1994 (20.15)
    - Noguchi Foundation, memoranda, budgets, 1990-1992 (20.16)
    - Noguchi Museum opening, guest lists, 1985 May (45.15)
    - Priscilla Morgan Study Center, 2010-2012 (20.17)
    - Schulman, Claire, dinner, 2001 (20.18)
    - Segerstrom funding of Noguchi Museum archives, 2011 (20.19)
    - [RESTRICTED] Settlement of Noguchi Estate, 1992-1996 (21.1 - 21.3)
    - Staffing, 1991 (21.4)
    - Strategic plan, correspondence, 2008-2009 (21.5 - 21.7)
    - Trustee file, Fulbright Awards Dinner, 2013 May (21.8)
    - Trustee correspondence, re Japanese works of art, 1991-1993 (21.9)
    - Wilson, Robert, installation, 2004 (21.10)
  - SPOLETO FESTIVAL
    - Art exhibition at 420 West Broadway, 1972 (45.16)
    - Artist lists, festival participants, 1958- 1973 (21.11)
    - Blackwood, Michael, film productions, 1969 (46.1)
    - Board minutes, 1973-1974 (46.2 - 46.5)
    - Board minutes, 1972 -1975 (21.12 - 21.14)
    - Boissevain, Ernest, correspondence, notes, 1974-1975 (22.1)
    - Brochures, 1958-1972 (22.2)
    - Budgets, expenditures, itineraries, 1968 -1975 (22.3 - 22.11, 46.6 - 46.7)
    - Business Committee for the Arts, Metropolitan Museum, 1971-1972 (22.12)
    - Calendars, social event scheduling, 1971 (46.8)
    - CBS broadcast, Gian Carlo Menotti, 1962-1963 (22.13)
    - Charleston, 2004 (22.14)
    - Consulting agreement, Charles Fabius, 2007 (22.15)
    - Correspondence, business/administrative, 1967-1975 (22.16, 23.1 - 23.8)
    - Daily schedules, 1972 (23.9)
    - de Kooning, Lisa, apprentice application, 1972 November (23.10)
    - Dome, Buckminster Fuller, notes, 1967 (23.11)
    - Friends of Spoleto, promotional text, correspondence, 1973-1974 (23.12)
    - Friends of Spoleto Evenings, 1971-1975 (23.13 - 23.14, 24.1 - 24.3)
    - Fundraising, 1967-1974 (24.4 - 24.7)
    - Fundraising, proposed Alice Tully Hall benefit, 1972-1973 (24.8)
    - Fundraising, benefit auction logistics, 1973-1974 (24.9 - 24.11)
    - Fundraising, Bloomingdales Friends of Spoleto Gala, 1973 (25.1)
    - Fundraising, correspondence, 1972-1975 (25.2)
    - Glass, Philip, Spoletosphere Concert, 1972 June (25.3)
    - Highpoint Spoleto Tour, 1973 (25.4)
    - Keene, Christopher, itineraries, press clippings, 1973-1974 (25.5)
    - Logistics, correspondence, 1966-1969 (25.6 - 25.8)
    - Miracle of Spoleto, essay by Gian Carlo Menotti, 1971 April (25.9)
    - National Endowment for the Arts, application, research, 1973-1975 (25.10 - 25.11)
    - National Orchestra Association reception, 1973 April (25.12)
    - New Music Research, 1973-1974 (25.13)
    - Noguchi Spoleto Play Sculptures, 1968-1971 (25.14)
    - Notes, lists, correspondence, 1969-1970 (25.15 - 25.18)
    - Oral history transcript, Priscilla Morgan interviewed by Gene Waddell, 1999 Apri (26.1 - 26.4)
    - Parties, event lists, 1974 (26.5)
    - Poster production, de Kooning, Frankenthaler, Lindner, Motherwell, Steinberg, 1969-1979 (26.6 - 26.11)
    - Morgan, Priscilla notes, 1975 (46.9)
    - Press relations, Publicity, 1965-1974 (26.12 - 26.13)
    - Robbins, Jerome, celebration, 1973-1974 (26.14)
    - Samuel Rubin Foundation, 1967-1974 (26.15)
    - Schedules, notes, 1973 (26.16)
    - Seating charts, Teatro Nuovo, Spoleto, undated (46.10)
    - Staff bios, correspondence, 1972-1974 (26.17)
    - Twyla Tharp promotion, 1975 (26.18)
    - VIP arrival logistics, lodging, 1970-1973 (26.19 - 26.20)
    - Wilson, Robert - logistics, Life and Times of Joseph Stalin, Einstein on the Beach, Letter for Queen Victoria, 1974-1975 (46.11 - 46.12)
    - World premiere lists, 1958-1973 (26.21)
  - TRAVEL
    - China, Festival of Music and Dance, 1977-1978 (27.1 - 27.2)
    - China, logistics, 1984 (27.3 - 27.4)
    - Costa Mesa, CA, 2006-2008 (27.5 - 27.6)
    - Europe, 1954-2008 (28.3 - 28.7, 29.1 - 29.8, 30.1 - 30.8, 31.1 - 31.7)
    - India, 1990-1995 (27.7)
    - Japan, 1984-1999 (27.8 - 27.11)
    - Los Angeles, CA, Martin Manulis Memorial, 2007 December (27.12)
    - Maine, 2003 (27.13)
    - Maps, printed materials, undated (31.8)
    - Mexico, 1989 (27.14)
    - Morocco, undated (28.1)
    - Texas, The Greenhouse, Arlington, 1985-1986 (28.2)
- Series II. Correspondence
  - Outgoing
    - 1950-1963 (32.1)
    - 1971-1976 (32.2)
    - 1986-1994 (32.3)
  - Incoming
    - 1950-1964 (32.4 - 32.11)
    - 1965 -1969 (33.1 - 33.8)
    - 1970-1974 (34.1 - 34.8, 43.3)
    - 1975-1979 (35.1 - 35.8)
    - 1980-1985 (36.1 - 36.8)
    - 1986-1991 (37.1 - 37.7)
    - 1992-2001 (38.1 - 38.10)
    - 2002-2007 (39.1 - 39.8)
    - 2008-2014 (40.1 - 40.8)
    - undated (43.2)
    - Albee, Edward, 1963-06-17 (41.1)
    - Angleton, Carmen, 1959-1992 (41.2)
    - Berman, Eugene, 1960-1970 (43.9)
    - Biddle Duke, Angier, 1962-1971 (41.3)
    - Bouche, Rene, 1954-1959 (41.4)
    - Calder, Alexander, 1959-04-21 (41.5)
    - Christo, 1969 (41.6)
    - Coe, Fred, 1956-1970 (41.7)
    - Coggeshall, Calvert, 1969-1973 (41.8)
    - Congdon, Don, 1985-1989 (41.9)
    - Cox, Mitchell, 1950-1954 (41.10)
    - Davis, John, 1962-1964 (41.11)
    - de Kooning, Elaine, undated (41.12)
    - de Kooning, Lisa, undated (41.13)
    - de Kooning, Willem, 1964 (41.14)
    - Fuller, Anne Hewlett, 1968-1972 (41.15)
    - Fuller, Buckminster, 1971, 1980 (41.16)
    - Graham, Martha, 1989 (41.17)
    - Guernsey, Otis, includes MS: Unicorn, 1962-1963 (41.18)
    - Hearon, Shelby, 1977-1981 (41.19)
    - Hua, Mao Jian, 1986 (41.20)
    - Johnson, H.B., 1945 (41.21)
    - Lewis, Salim, 1952-1955 (41.22)
    - Manulis, Martin, 1960-1985 (41.23)
    - Matta, Malitte, 1970-1977 (41.24)
    - Menotti, Gian Carlo, 1965-1970 (41.25)
    - Mosel, Tad, 1963 -1964, 1992 (42.1)
    - O'Hara, Frank, 1962-01-08 (42.4)
    - Penrose, Roland, 1983-09-24 (42.5)
    - Rawlings, John, 1957-1963 (43.10)
    - Reinhardt, Ad, 1962 (42.6)
    - Rockefeller, Larry, 1970 (42.7)
    - Sadao, Shoji, 1968-1973 (42.8)
    - Smith, David, 1961, 1965 (42.9)
    - Smith, David, to P.M., note written on blank check, undated (42.10)
    - Turner, Tess, 1965-1966 (42.11)
    - Tworkov, Jack, 1959-1972 (42.12)
    - Angleton, Carmen, 2003-04-10 (42.13)
    - Whitney, John Hay, 1960 (42.14)
    - Wilson, Robert, 1975-2011 (42.15)
  - Mixed
    - Morgan, Henry and Marian (parents), correspondence to/from Priscilla Morgan, 1840, 1911, 1953-1962 (41.26 - 41.27)
    - Noguchi, Isamu - to/from Priscilla Morgan, photocopies, 1960-1973 (42.2 - 42.3, 43.4 - 43.8)
- Series III. Photographs
  - Cummings, Ralph Waldo, circa 1950-1959 (47.1)
  - Fuller, Buckminster and Morgan, Priscilla, 1970-1983 (47.2)
  - Fuller, Buckminster, slides taken by Isamu Noguchi, India, Nehru Memorial, 1969 (47.3)
  - Harlem Theater Workshop, building facade, 1972 (47.4)
  - Morgan, Priscilla, childhood, family, circa 1910-1919, circa 1940-1949 (47.5 - 47.6)
  - Morgan, Priscilla, 90th birthday, 2009 (47.7)
  - Menotti, Gian Carlo, undated (47.8)
  - Menotti, Martin's Lie, 1964 (47.9)
  - Noguchi, Isamu, childhood, circa 1910 (47.10)
  - Noguchi, Isamu, Morgan, Priscilla, undated (47.11)
  - Noguchi Fountain, Plaza, Detroit, MI, 1973 (47.12)
  - Noguchi Sculptures, undated (47.13)
  - Travel, including Japan, circa 1950-1999 (47.14)
  - Unidentified, children, friends, family, circa 1970, 1980-1999 (47.15 - 47.16)
  - Scrapbook photo album, Sapporo Art Park, 1997 October (47.17)
  - Vassar exhibition re Priscilla Morgan, 2007 (47.18)
  - Vassar, circa 1920-1939 (47.19)
  - Negatives, unidentified, circa 1940-1959 (47.20)
  - (2) photo albums, Japan, New York, Italy, Noguchi, circa 1970-1989 (48)